<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<items>
<item>
<title><![CDATA[Clinical Efficacy of Targeted Biologic Agents as Second-Line Therapy of Advanced Thyroid Cancer]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0250v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Introduction.</b> Targeted biologic agents showed clinically meaningful efficacy as front-line therapy for advanced radioiodine-refractory and medullary thyroid cancer. The clinical benefit of these agents beyond the front line has yet to be established.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> We assessed the clinical benefit of targeted agents in patients with advanced differentiated and medullary thyroid cancer treated at a single academic cancer center. We determined efficacy and compared front-line and second-line benefit using biochemical and anatomic response, time to treatment failure, and progression-free survival (PFS). Statistical differences were assessed by <I>t</I> test and chi-square test. Survival curves were generated by the Kaplan-Meier method. Differences in survival were assessed using the log-rank test, and a <I>p</I> value &lt;.05 was considered significant.</p><p><b>Results.</b> We identified 39 patients with advanced differentiated and medullary thyroid cancer treated with targeted biologic agents. Median age was 56.3 years. Overall, 25 men and 14 women participated. Histology showed 23% medullary and 77% differentiated cancer. Nineteen patients progressed on front-line therapy and subsequently received second-line therapy. Targeted agents conferred clinically meaningful benefit in the second-line setting in terms of biochemical response (13.3%), clinical benefit (83.3%), median time to treatment failure (4.0 months; 95% confidence interval: 2.6&ndash;8.2), and median PFS (4.6 months; 95% confidence interval: 3.2&ndash;8.2). Second-line benefit (median PFS) was more modest in comparison to the front-line setting in both genders (women: 3 months vs. 12.2 months; men: 6 months vs. 19.7 months), in differentiated cancers (4.1 months vs. 15.7 months), and with vascular targeting agents (4.4 months vs. 20.1 months).</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> Patients with advanced thyroid cancer derived meaningful clinical benefit from additional therapy with a biologic agent following disease progression on front-line targeted therapy.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</items>