<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<rdf:RDF
 xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
 xmlns="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/"
 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
 xmlns:taxo="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/taxonomy/"
 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
 xmlns:syn="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
 xmlns:prism="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/prism/"
 xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
>

<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0250v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Clinical Efficacy of Targeted Biologic Agents as Second-Line Therapy of Advanced Thyroid Cancer]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0250v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Introduction.</b> Targeted biologic agents showed clinically meaningful efficacy as front-line therapy for advanced radioiodine-refractory and medullary thyroid cancer. The clinical benefit of these agents beyond the front line has yet to be established.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> We assessed the clinical benefit of targeted agents in patients with advanced differentiated and medullary thyroid cancer treated at a single academic cancer center. We determined efficacy and compared front-line and second-line benefit using biochemical and anatomic response, time to treatment failure, and progression-free survival (PFS). Statistical differences were assessed by <I>t</I> test and chi-square test. Survival curves were generated by the Kaplan-Meier method. Differences in survival were assessed using the log-rank test, and a <I>p</I> value &lt;.05 was considered significant.</p><p><b>Results.</b> We identified 39 patients with advanced differentiated and medullary thyroid cancer treated with targeted biologic agents. Median age was 56.3 years. Overall, 25 men and 14 women participated. Histology showed 23% medullary and 77% differentiated cancer. Nineteen patients progressed on front-line therapy and subsequently received second-line therapy. Targeted agents conferred clinically meaningful benefit in the second-line setting in terms of biochemical response (13.3%), clinical benefit (83.3%), median time to treatment failure (4.0 months; 95% confidence interval: 2.6&ndash;8.2), and median PFS (4.6 months; 95% confidence interval: 3.2&ndash;8.2). Second-line benefit (median PFS) was more modest in comparison to the front-line setting in both genders (women: 3 months vs. 12.2 months; men: 6 months vs. 19.7 months), in differentiated cancers (4.1 months vs. 15.7 months), and with vascular targeting agents (4.4 months vs. 20.1 months).</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> Patients with advanced thyroid cancer derived meaningful clinical benefit from additional therapy with a biologic agent following disease progression on front-line targeted therapy.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Owonikoko, T. K., Chowdry, R. P., Chen, Z., Kim, S., Saba, N. F., Shin, D. M., Khuri, F. R.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-23T09:40:23-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0250</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0250</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Clinical Efficacy of Targeted Biologic Agents as Second-Line Therapy of Advanced Thyroid Cancer]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-23</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>ENDOCRINOLOGY</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0202v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Barriers to Study Enrollment in Patients With Advanced Cancer Referred to a Phase I Clinical Trials Unit]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0202v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b><I>Background. </I></b>We conducted this retrospective study to identify reasons that patients referred to a phase I clinical trial failed to enroll or delayed enrollment onto the trial.</p><p><b><I>Materials and Methods. </I></b>Outcome analyses were conducted independently on data collected from electronic medical records of two sets of consecutive patients referred to a phase I clinical trial facility at MD Anderson Cancer Center. Data from the first set of 300 patients were used to determine relevant variables affecting enrollment; data from the second set of 957 patients were then analyzed for these variables.</p><p><b><I>Results. </I></b>Results from the two sets of patients were similar. Approximately 55% of patients were enrolled in a phase I trial. Patients referred from within MD Anderson were more likely to be enrolled than patients seen originally outside the institution (<I>p</I> = .006); black patients were more likely than white patients to enroll (69% vs. 43%; <I>p</I> = .04). The median interval from the initial visit to initiation of treatments was 19 days. Major reasons for failure to enroll included failure to return to the clinic (36%), opting for treatment in another clinic (17%), hospice referral (11%), early death (10%), and lack of financial clearance (5%). Treatment was delayed for three weeks or more in 250 patients; in 85 patients (34%), the delay was caused by financial and insurance issues.</p><p><b><I>Conclusion. </I></b>Failure to return to the clinic, pursuit of other therapy, and rapid deterioration were the major reasons for failure to enroll; lengthy financial clearance was the most common reason for delayed enrollment onto a phase I trial. </p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fu, S., McQuinn, L., Naing, A., Wheler, J. J., Janku, F., Falchook, G. S., Piha-Paul, S. A., Tu, D., Howard, A., Tsimberidou, A., Zinner, R., Hong, D. S., Kurzrock, R.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-23T09:40:22-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0202</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0202</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Barriers to Study Enrollment in Patients With Advanced Cancer Referred to a Phase I Clinical Trials Unit]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-23</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>OUTCOMES RESEARCH</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0138v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Anti-Mullerian Hormone and Antral Follicle Count Reveal a Late Impairment of Ovarian Reserve in Patients Undergoing Low-Gonadotoxic Regimens for Hematological Malignancies]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0138v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The impact of cancer therapy on the reproductive potential of patients is increasingly recognized because survival rates of patients have clearly improved in recent years. Different fertility preservation methods, either generally accepted or still experimental, are currently available, and counseling of patients requires a delicate balance between the efficacy and side effects of the proposed method and the characteristics of both the tumor and the therapy. Deeper knowledge of the effects of cancer therapy on the reproductive potential of patients over time is required to identify the most appropriate fertility preservation method. In this paper, we report a case-control study in which female patients who were diagnosed with hematological malignancies and treated with chemotherapy and/or radiotherapy were compared with age-matched controls in terms of ovarian reserve, as measured by ultrasound examination and hormonal status. By stratifying patients for gonadotoxicity of the therapy received and time elapsed from the end of the therapy, we report that patients treated with low gonadotoxic therapies, while being similar to age-matched controls in their ovarian reserve when evaluated within few years from the end of the therapy, show a clear impairment over longer times. We also report that anti-M&uuml;llerian hormone is the most sensitive hormonal parameter in detecting changes in ovarian reserve when compared with follicle-stimulating hormone or inhibin-B. This study stresses the importance of accurate counseling at the time of diagnosis of cancer and emphasizes the risks of infertility with low gonadotoxic therapies that may reduce the reproductive window of survivors.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Di Paola, R., Costantini, C., Tecchio, C., Salvagno, G. L., Montemezzi, R., Perandini, A., Pizzolo, G., Zaffagnini, S., Franchi, M.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-22T12:02:55-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0138</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0138</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Anti-Mullerian Hormone and Antral Follicle Count Reveal a Late Impairment of Ovarian Reserve in Patients Undergoing Low-Gonadotoxic Regimens for Hematological Malignancies]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-22</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>GYNECOLOGIC ONCOLOGY</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0186v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Impact of Molecular Alterations and Targeted Therapy in Appendiceal Adenocarcinomas]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0186v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Background.</b> Appendiceal adenocarcinomas (AAs) are rare and this has limited their molecular understanding. The purpose of our study was to characterize the molecular profile of AA and explore the role of targeted therapy against cyclooxygenase-2 (COX-2) and epidermal growth factor receptor (<I>EGFR</I>).</p><p><b>Patients and Methods.</b> We performed a retrospective review of 607 patients with AA at a single institution. A total of 149 patients underwent molecular testing for at least one of the following: activating mutations in <I>KRAS, BRAF</I>, cKIT, <I>EGFR,</I> or <I>PI3K</I>; protein expression of c-KIT or COX-2; or microsatellite instability (MSI) status by immunohistochemistry. Kaplan-Meier product limit method and log-rank test were used to estimate overall survival (OS) and to determine associations among OS, COX-2 expression, <I>KRAS</I> mutations, and other characteristics.</p><p><b>Results.</b> Age, grade, stage, signet ring cells, mucinous histology, and completeness of cytoreduction score correlated with survival outcomes. COX-2 expression, <I>KRAS, PI3K</I>, and <I>BRAF</I> mutations were seen in 61%, 55%, 17%, and 4% of patients, respectively. High MSI was seen in 6% of patients. <I>KRAS</I> mutation was strongly associated with well differentiated or moderately differentiated AA (<I>p</I> &lt; .01). COX-2 expression (<I>p</I> = .33) and the presence of <I>KRAS</I> mutation (<I>p</I> = .91) had no impact on OS. The use of celecoxib in patients whose tumors expressed COX-2 (<I>p</I> = .84) and the use of cetuximab or panitumumab in patients with <I>KRAS</I> wild-type tumors (<I>p</I> = .83) also had no impact on OS.</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> In this cohort, we demonstrated that COX-2 expression and <I>KRAS</I> mutations were frequently seen in AA, although neither exhibited any prognostic significance. MSI was infrequent in AA. Targeted therapy against COX-2 and <I>EGFR</I> appeared to provide no clinical benefit. Well and moderately differentiated AA were molecularly distinct from poorly differentiated AA.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Raghav, K. P. S., Shetty, A. V., Kazmi, S. M. A., Zhang, N., Morris, J., Taggart, M., Fournier, K., Royal, R., Mansfield, P., Eng, C., Wolff, R. A., Overman, M. J.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-22T12:02:55-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0186</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0186</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Impact of Molecular Alterations and Targeted Therapy in Appendiceal Adenocarcinomas]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-22</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>GASTROINTESTINAL CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0135v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Pilot Studies for Personalized Cancer Medicine: Focusing on the Patient for Treatment Selection]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0135v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Advances in diagnostics and targeted therapies during the past decade have changed how oncology is viewed. "Stratified medicine" has emerged from the accumulated evidence garnered from matching targeted therapies with tumor molecular aberrations. Concomitantly, current knowledge derived from large-scale, massively parallel sequencing technologies and global research initiatives such as the international 1000 Genomes Project, the Cancer Genome Atlas, the International Cancer Genome Consortium, and publicly available catalogs such as the Catalogue of Somatic Mutations in Cancer and Genomics of Drug Sensitivity in Cancer have illuminated the utility of understanding the molecular basis of cancer through genome analysis. In addition, multiple collaborative efforts are widening the possibility of universally personalizing cancer care. Although several key challenges of personalized cancer medicine (PCM) need to be addressed, some pilot studies are transforming the way we analyze tumor tissue molecular aberrations, design clinical trials, and measure treatment efficacy. Taken together, these pilot studies are paving the way for clinical trials that are designed to empirically test the concept of PCM. In this paper, we describe lessons learned from the first pilot initiatives of PCM and how this knowledge is being used to design novel clinical trials.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[De Mattos-Arruda, L., Rodon, J.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-17T13:21:26-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0135</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0135</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Pilot Studies for Personalized Cancer Medicine: Focusing on the Patient for Treatment Selection]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-17</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>CANCER DIAGNOSTICS AND MOLECULAR PATHOLOGY</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0167v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Breast Cancer Multifocality and Multicentricity and Locoregional Recurrence]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0167v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Background.</b> The impact of multifocal (MF) or multicentric (MC) breast cancer on locoregional (LR) control rates is unknown.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> MF was defined as two or more separate invasive tumors in the same quadrant of the breast. MC was defined as two or more separate invasive tumors occupying more than one quadrant of the same breast. Patients were categorized by LR treatment: breast conservation therapy (BCT; <I>n</I> = 256), mastectomy (<I>n</I> = 466), or mastectomy plus postmastectomy radiation therapy (PMRT; <I>n</I> = 184). All patients with MC disease had mastectomy (10 patients treated with BCT for MC disease were excluded). The Kaplan-Meier product limit method was used to calculate 5-year LR control rate. Cox proportional hazards models were used to determine independent associations of multifocality or multicentricity with LR control.</p><p><b>Results.</b> A total of 906 patients had either MF disease (<I>n</I> = 673) or MC disease (<I>n</I> = 233). With median follow-up of 52 months, the 5-year LR control rate was 99% for MF, 96% for MC, and 98% for unifocal tumors (<I>p</I> = .44). Subset analysis revealed no difference in LR control regardless of the LR treatment (<I>p</I> = .67 for BCT, <I>p</I> = .37 for mastectomy, <I>p</I> = .29 for mastectomy plus PMRT). There were five in-breast recurrences after BCT in the MF group. MF and MC did not have an independent impact on LR control rate on multivariate analysis.</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> MF and MC disease are not independent risk factors for LR recurrence. Patients with MF and MC breast cancer had rates of LR control similar to those of their unifocal counterparts. These data suggest that BCT is a safe option for patients with MF tumors and that MF or MC disease alone is not an indication for PMRT.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynch, S. P., Lei, X., Hsu, L., Meric-Bernstam, F., Buchholz, T. A., Zhang, H., Hortobagyi, G. N., Gonzalez-Angulo, A. M., Valero, V.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-17T13:21:26-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0167</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0167</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Breast Cancer Multifocality and Multicentricity and Locoregional Recurrence]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-17</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>BREAST CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2012-0361v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Optimizing Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor Therapy in Gastrointestinal Stromal Tumors: Exploring the Benefits of Continuous Kinase Suppression]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2012-0361v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Background.</b> The oral tyrosine kinase inhibitor (TKI) imatinib has revolutionized the treatment of gastrointestinal stromal tumors (GISTs), most of which harbor oncogenic mutation in genes that encode the receptor tyrosine kinases KIT or PDGFA. Imatinib is the standard of care for patients with advanced GIST and for patients with primary GIST at significant risk of recurrence after surgery.</p><p><b>Design.</b> This review discusses data supporting continuous kinase suppression with imatinib and key issues, including response to imatinib reintroduction, effect of treatment interruption on secondary resistance to imatinib, and prognostic factors associated with sustained response to imatinib.</p><p><b>Results.</b> Long-term follow-up results of the B2222 study and updated results of the BFR14 trial demonstrate that continuous imatinib treatment in patients with advanced GIST is associated with reduced risk of progression. For patients progressing on or intolerant of imatinib, continuing therapy with TKIs sunitinib followed by regorafenib is recommended. In the adjuvant setting, final results of the trial by the Scandinavian Sarcoma Group and the Sarcoma Group of the Arbeitsgemeinschaft Internistische Onkologie demonstrate that 3 years of adjuvant imatinib, compared with 1 year, significantly reduces the risk of recurrence and improves overall survival of patients with KIT-positive GIST at high risk of recurrence.</p><p><b>Conclusions.</b> Maintenance of therapy with TKIs is the key to successful treatment of GIST. Results from recent studies provide a strong rationale for continuous imatinib treatment for 3 years following surgical resection and long-term continuous administration in advanced or metastatic GIST.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Le Cesne, A., Blay, J.-Y., Reichardt, P., Joensuu, H.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-17T13:21:26-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2012-0361</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2012-0361</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Optimizing Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitor Therapy in Gastrointestinal Stromal Tumors: Exploring the Benefits of Continuous Kinase Suppression]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-17</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>GASTROINTESTINAL CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0224v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Treatment of Dexamethasone-Induced Hiccup in Chemotherapy Patients by Methylprednisolone Rotation]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0224v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b><I>Background.</I></b> Dexamethasone-induced hiccup (DIH) is an underrecognized symptom in patients with cancer, and little information is available about its treatment. The aims of this study were to investigate the feasibility of methylprednisolone rotation as treatment and to confirm the male predominance among those with cancer who experienced DIH during chemotherapy.</p><p><b><I>Methods.</I></b> Persons with cancer who experienced hiccups during chemotherapy treatment and who were receiving treatment with dexamethasone were presumed to have DIH. The following algorithmic practice was implemented for antiemetic corticosteroid use: rotation from dexamethasone to methylprednisolone in the next cycle and dexamethasone re-administration in the second cycle of chemotherapy after recognition of hiccups to confirm DIH. All other antiemetics except corticosteroid remained unchanged. Patients (<I>n</I> = 40) were recruited from eight cancer centers in Korea from September 2012 to April 2013. Data were collected retrospectively.</p><p><b><I>Results.</I></b> Hiccup intensity (numeric rating scale [NRS]: 5.38 vs. 0.53) and duration (68.44 minutes vs. 1.79 minutes) were significantly decreased after rotation to methylprednisolone, while intensity of emesis was not increased (NRS: 2.63 vs. 2.08). Median dose of dexamethasone and methylprednisolone were 10 mg and 50 mg, respectively. Thirty-four (85%) of 40 patients showed complete resolution of hiccups after methylprednisolone rotation in the next cycle. Of these 34 patients, 25 (73.5%) had recurrence of hiccups after dexamethasone re-administration. Compared with baseline values, hiccup intensity (NRS: 5.24 vs. 2.44) and duration (66.43 minutes vs. 22.00 minutes) were significantly attenuated after dexamethasone re-administration. Of the 40 eligible patients, 38 (95%) were male.</p><p><b><I>Conclusion.</I></b> DIH during chemotherapy could be controlled without losing antiemetic potential by replacing dexamethasone with methylprednisolone. We also identified a male predominance of DIH. Further prospective studies are warranted.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lee, G.-W., Oh, S. Y., Kang, M. H., Kang, J. H., Park, S. H., Hwang, I. G., Yi, S. Y., Choi, Y. J., Ji, J. H., Lee, H. Y., Bruera, E.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-09T09:50:20-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0224</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0224</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Treatment of Dexamethasone-Induced Hiccup in Chemotherapy Patients by Methylprednisolone Rotation]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-09</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>SYMPTOM MANAGEMENT AND SUPPORTIVE CARE</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0175v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Hope, Quality of Life, and Benefit From Treatment in Women Having Chemotherapy for Platinum-Resistant/Refractory Recurrent Ovarian Cancer: The Gynecologic Cancer Intergroup Symptom Benefit Study]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0175v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b><I>Purpose.</I></b> Chemotherapy for platinum-resistant/refractory ovarian cancer is motivated by the hope of benefit. We sought to determine the relationships between: (a) trait hope, expectation of symptom benefit from chemotherapy, and anxiety and depression; (b) hope and perceived efficacy of chemotherapy; and (c) unfulfilled hope (where expectations for benefit are not fulfilled) and depression.</p><p><b><I>Methods.</I></b> Adult patients enrolled within stage 1 of the Gynecologic Cancer Intergroup Symptom Benefit Study were included.</p><p><b><I>Patient.</I></b> Reported outcomes were collected from 126 women with predominantly platinum-resistant ovarian cancer at baseline, prior to the first four treatment cycles (12&ndash;16 weeks), and four weeks after completing chemotherapy or at disease progression, whichever came first. Associations were assessed with Spearman rank correlation coefficient (<I>r</I>) and odds ratio.</p><p><b><I>Results.</I></b> Trait hope and expectation of symptom benefit from chemotherapy were weakly correlated with each other (<I>r</I> = 0.25). Trait hope, but not expectation of symptom benefit, was negatively correlated with anxiety (<I>r</I> = &ndash;0.43) and depression (<I>r</I> = &ndash;0.50). The smaller the discrepancy between perceived and expected symptom benefit, the less likely the patient was to have scores indicative of depression (odds ratio: 0.68; 95% confidence interval: 0.49&ndash;0.96; <I>p</I> = .026).</p><p><b><I>Conclusion.</I></b> Trait hope and expectation of symptom benefit from chemotherapy appear to be distinct and independent of the aspects of quality of life and scores for depression. Hope did not appear to affect perceived efficacy of chemotherapy in alleviating symptoms, but women whose expectation of symptom benefit from chemotherapy was not fulfilled were more likely to have scores indicative of depression. It may be preferable to encourage hope toward achievable goals rather than toward benefits from chemotherapy.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sjoquist, K. M., Friedlander, M. L., O'Connell, R. L., Voysey, M., King, M. T., Stockler, M. R., Oza, A. M., Gillies, K., Martyn, J. K., Butow, P. N.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-09T09:50:20-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0175</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0175</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Hope, Quality of Life, and Benefit From Treatment in Women Having Chemotherapy for Platinum-Resistant/Refractory Recurrent Ovarian Cancer: The Gynecologic Cancer Intergroup Symptom Benefit Study]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-09</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>BREAST CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0061v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[A Double-Blind, Randomized Phase II Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Acetyl-L-Carnitine in the Prevention of Sagopilone-Induced Peripheral Neuropathy]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0061v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Background.</b> Peripheral neuropathy (PN) is a recognized side effect of microtubule-targeting agents and the most clinically relevant toxicity observed with the epothilone sagopilone (SAG). Studies suggest that acetyl-L-carnitine (ALC) may prevent chemotherapy-induced PN. We conducted a prospective, placebo (PBO)-controlled, double-blind, randomized trial to investigate the safety and efficacy of ALC for the prevention of SAG-induced PN.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> Patients with ovarian cancer (OC) or castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC) and no evidence of neuropathy received SAG (16 mg/m<sup>2</sup> intravenously over 3 hours every 3 weeks) with ALC (1,000 mg every 3 days) or placebo (PBO). The primary endpoint was incidence of PN within six or fewer cycles in both treatment groups.</p><p><b>Results.</b> Overall, 150 patients enrolled (98 OC patients, 52 CRPC patients), with 75 per treatment arm. No significant difference in overall PN incidence was observed between treatment arms. The incidence of grade &ge;3 PN was significantly lower in the ALC arm in OC patients. Median duration of neuropathy was similar between treatment arms. The best overall response (according to the modified Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumors), response according to tumor markers, time-to-event variables, and discontinuations because of adverse events (AEs) were comparable between treatment arms.</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> Administration of ALC with SAG did not result in a significant difference in overall PN incidence compared with a PBO. OC patients in the SAG/ALC arm had a significantly lower incidence of grade 3 or 4 PN compared with OC patients in the SAG/PBO arm.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campone, M., Berton-Rigaud, D., Joly-Lobbedez, F., Baurain, J.-F., Rolland, F., Stenzl, A., Fabbro, M., van Dijk, M., Pinkert, J., Schmelter, T., de Bont, N., Pautier, P.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-08T11:48:00-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0061</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0061</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[A Double-Blind, Randomized Phase II Study to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of Acetyl-L-Carnitine in the Prevention of Sagopilone-Induced Peripheral Neuropathy]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-08</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>CLINICAL TRIAL RESULTS</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0223v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[A Randomized Study of Interferon {alpha}-2b Versus No Treatment as Consolidation After High Dose Therapy and Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation for Patients With Relapsed Lymphoma]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0223v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Background.</b> Patients with lymphoma who have experienced a first relapse or progression and have disease deemed sensitive to salvage chemotherapy nevertheless have a high likelihood of having a second relapse. To decrease the likelihood of a second relapse after high-dose therapy (HDT) and autologous stem cell transplantation (ASCT), interferon (IFN) &alpha;-2b was given in a prospective randomized international trial.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> In this trial, 221 patients with varying histologic diagnoses (8 small lymphocytic, 37 follicular, 9 mantle, 90 diffuse large B-cell, 20 peripheral T-cell, 3 high-grade B-cell non-Hodgkin lymphoma, and 54 Hodgkin lymphoma) were randomly assigned to receive no further treatment (arm A: 117 patients) or IFN&alpha;-2b, 3 MU three times weekly, for 18 months (arm B: 104 patients).</p><p><b>Results.</b> In arm B, 21 patients (20%) did not receive IFN&alpha;-2b because of early progression or absence of hematologic recovery, 29 patients (28%) completed the 18 months of treatment, and 54 patients (52%) interrupted treatment because of progression (23%) or toxicity (29%). Event-free survival and overall survival were not different between the two arms on an intent-to-treat analysis and also if analysis was restricted to patients who were alive and had not experienced disease progression three months after transplantation. The study was not sufficiently powered to evaluate effects in histologic subtypes.</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> In this trial, post-autograft IFN&alpha;-2b did not improve outcomes in a heterogeneous group of patients with lymphoma.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Bosly, A., Grigg, A., Holte, H., Gisselbrecht, C., Radford, J., Rossi, A., Lopez-Guillermo, A., Trneny, M., Sebban, C., Hagberg, H., Leal da Costa, F., Colombat, P., Bron, D., Coiffier, B.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-08T11:48:00-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0223</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0223</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[A Randomized Study of Interferon {alpha}-2b Versus No Treatment as Consolidation After High Dose Therapy and Autologous Stem Cell Transplantation for Patients With Relapsed Lymphoma]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-08</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>CLINICAL TRIAL RESULTS</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0171v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[What Lies Within: Novel Strategies in Immunotherapy for Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0171v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Introduction.</b> Immunotherapy has become an increasingly important therapeutic strategy for those with cancer, with phase III studies demonstrating survival advantages in melanoma and castration-resistant prostate cancer. Non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) is a promising target for the next generation of immune-based strategies. In this article, we examine the current state of the art in lung cancer immunotherapy, including vaccines that specifically target lung tumor antigens and immune checkpoint antibodies such as antiprogrammed death 1 (anti-PD-1). Both approaches harness innate immunity against tumors by suppressing tumor-induced immune paresis.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> To identify relevant clinical trials of immunotherapy in NSCLC, PubMed and Medline databases were searched using the terms "immunotherapy" and "NSCLC," and several other therapy-specific search terms (e.g., PD-1, NSCLC). Additionally, abstracts presented at international lung cancer symposia, the American Society of Clinical Oncology annual meeting, and the European Society of Medical Oncology annual meeting between 2005 and 2013 were evaluated.</p><p><b>Results.</b> Large international phase III trials of NSCLC vaccines have completed accrual in both the adjuvant and metastatic disease settings. Results of the START study were disappointing, but results from other studies are still awaited. Immune checkpoint modulation has shown promise, with separate phase I studies of the anti-PD-1 antibody, nivolumab, and anti-PD-L1 antibody, MPDL3280A, demonstrating good tolerance and durable responses for certain patients with NSCLC who were heavily pretreated.</p><p><b>Conclusions.</b> Immune-based strategies have shown initial promise for early- and advanced-stage NSCLC. Validating these findings in randomized studies and discovering durable biomarkers of response represent the next challenges for investigation.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Forde, P. M., Reiss, K. A., Zeidan, A. M., Brahmer, J. R.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-10-08T11:48:00-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0171</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0171</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[What Lies Within: Novel Strategies in Immunotherapy for Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-10-08</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>LUNG CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0168v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Chemotherapy With Erlotinib or Chemotherapy Alone in Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer With Acquired Resistance to EGFR Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0168v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Purpose.</b> Epidermal growth factor receptor (<I>EGFR</I>)-mutant non-small cell lung cancer has an oncogene-addicted biology that confers sensitivity to EGFR tyrosine kinase inhibitors (TKIs). Published data suggest that EGFR addiction persists after development of TKI acquired resistance, leading many clinicians to continue TKI with subsequent chemotherapy; however, this strategy has not been formally evaluated.</p><p><b>Methods.</b> We retrospectively reviewed an institutional database to identify patients with advanced <I>EGFR</I> mutation with acquired resistance who subsequently received chemotherapy. Patients were classified as receiving chemotherapy with continued erlotinib or chemotherapy alone. We assessed differences in outcomes between the two strategies.</p><p><b>Results.</b> Seventy-eight patients were included, 34 treated with chemotherapy and erlotinib and 44 treated with chemotherapy alone. Objective response rate was evaluable in 57 patients and was 41% for those treated with chemotherapy and erlotinib and 18% for those treated with chemotherapy alone. After adjusting for chemotherapy regimen and length of initial TKI course, the odds ratio for the response rate was 0.20 (95% confidence interval: 0.05&ndash;0.78; <I>p</I> = .02) favoring treatment with chemotherapy and erlotinib. The median progression-free survival was 4.4 months on chemotherapy and erlotinib and 4.2 months on chemotherapy alone (adjusted hazard ratio = 0.79; 95% confidence interval: 0.48&ndash;1.29; <I>p</I> = .34). There was no difference in overall survival.</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b> This is the first study, to our knowledge, to demonstrate that continuation of EGFR TKI with chemotherapy in patients with acquired resistance improves outcomes compared with chemotherapy alone. We observed an improved response rate but no difference in progression-free survival or overall survival. A larger prospective clinical trial is needed to evaluate this promising strategy further.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Goldberg, S. B., Oxnard, G. R., Digumarthy, S., Muzikansky, A., Jackman, D. M., Lennes, I. T., Sequist, L. V.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-09-26T07:43:06-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0168</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0168</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Chemotherapy With Erlotinib or Chemotherapy Alone in Advanced Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer With Acquired Resistance to EGFR Tyrosine Kinase Inhibitors]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-09-26</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>LUNG CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0160v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Bevacizumab for Advanced Breast Cancer: Hope, Hype, and Hundreds of Headlines]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0160v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p><b>Introduction.</b>On February 22, 2008, the Food and Drug Administration granted accelerated approval for the use of bevacizumab (Avastin) in metastatic breast cancer. Based on subsequent clinical trials, this approval was revoked on November 18, 2011. In this study, we categorize and analyze the newspaper reports related to bevacizumab&rsquo;s use in advanced breast cancer.</p><p><b>Methods.</b>Using the Factiva media database, we reviewed all newspaper reports published in North America from January 4, 2002, to January 4, 2013, containing the words "breast cancer" and "Avastin," or "bevacizumab." Articles were classified as pre-approval (January 4, 2002&ndash;February 21, 2008), approval (February 22, 2008&ndash;November 17, 2011), or post-approval loss (November 18, 2011&ndash;January 4, 2013). Information regarding benefits, side effects, costs, interviewees, and article tone and theme were abstracted from each article by two independent reviewers. Differences among the three study phases were compared using the chi square analysis.</p><p><b>Results.</b>A total of 359 articles met study inclusion criteria. The number of reports having a positive headline tone and/or positive article tone declined with each study period. The proportion of articles discussing side effects and financial costs increased, whereas those discussing efficacy decreased with each study period. Drug representatives were most likely to be quoted in newspaper articles prior to bevacizumab&rsquo;s approval.</p><p><b>Conclusion.</b>Media reports are a common source of medical information for patients, practitioners, and policy makers. We observed substantial fluidity of media reports over time.</p>]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fralick, M., Ray, M., Fung, C., Booth, C. M., Mallick, R., Clemons, M. J.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-09-26T07:43:05-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0160</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0160</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Bevacizumab for Advanced Breast Cancer: Hope, Hype, and Hundreds of Headlines]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-09-26</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>BREAST CANCER</prism:section>
</item>
<item rdf:about="http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0173v1?rss=1">
<title><![CDATA[Lost in Transition? Thoughts on Retirement--"Will You Still Need Me, Will You Still Feed Me, When I'm Sixty-Four?"]]></title>
<link>http://theoncologist.alphamedpress.org/cgi/content/short/theoncologist.2013-0173v1?rss=1</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<dc:creator><![CDATA[Clemons, M. J., Vandermeer, L. A., Gunstone, I., Jacobs, C., Kaizer, L., Paterson, A. H.]]></dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-09-16T08:50:05-07:00</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>info:doi/10.1634/theoncologist.2013-0173</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>hwp:master-id:theoncologist;theoncologist.2013-0173</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>AlphaMed Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:title><![CDATA[Lost in Transition? Thoughts on Retirement--"Will You Still Need Me, Will You Still Feed Me, When I'm Sixty-Four?"]]></dc:title>
<prism:publicationDate>2013-09-16</prism:publicationDate>
<prism:section>REFLECTIONS</prism:section>
</item>
</rdf:RDF>